A Guide to the Markle Foundation records, Accessions 1997-2008, Record Group 4 FA785
Rockefeller Archive Center
Markle Foundation records, Accessions 1997-2008, Record Group 4
1927-2008
Rockefeller Archive Center
John and Mary R. Markle Foundation
FA785
208.42 Cubic Feet 85 document boxes, 1 half-box, 1 flat file, and 133 record storage boxes.
Arrangement
Series 1: Administrative Files. Series 2: Grant and Grantee Files. Series 3: Henry Geller papers. Series 4: Financial records. Series 5: Lloyd N. Morrisett files. Series 6: Cathy Clark files. Series 7: Edith Bjornson files. Series 8: Accession 2000:016. Series 9: Accession 2008:073.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 15 years old are open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Records were donated to RAC by the Markle Foundation in 2008. The archival material was physically transferred in multipe accessions spanning 1997-2008.
Scope and Contents
Records include: Grant and Grantee files, correspondence, Board of Directors materials, Annual reports, and a small selection of building and office files.
- Administrative Files, 1927-2008; 1; 21.65 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement
  The Administrative records are arranged in 7 subseries as follows: 1. Annual Reports. 2. Board of Directors Meeting Agendas. 3. Minutes. 4. Chronological Correspondence. 5. Former Board of Directors Minutes. 6. Building and Office Files. 7. Miscellaneous.
  - Markle Foundation Annual Reports, 1935-1969, 1993-1995, 1997; 1
    Annual reports
    - Annual Reports, 1935-1944; 2 copies (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1945-1650; 2 copies (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1951-1957; 2 copies (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1957-1963; 2 copies (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1963-1969; 2 copies (Box 1)
    - Markle Foundation Annual Report 1993 (Item REF 361.763 2 JOH 1993)
    - Markle Foundation Annual Report 1994 (Item REF 361.763 2 JOH 1994)
    - Markle Foundation Annual Report 1995 (Item REF 361.763 2 1995)
    - Markle Foundation Annual Report 1997 (Item REF 361.763 2 JOH 1997)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agendas, 1969-2008; 2
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1969 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1969 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1969 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1970 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1970 June 11 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1970 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1971 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1971 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1971 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1971 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1972 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1972 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1972 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1973 March 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1973 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1973 November 5 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1974 March 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1974 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1974 November 22 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1975 March 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1975 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1975 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1976 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1976 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1976 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1976 Nov 23 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1977 March 7 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1977 June 14 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1977 November 28 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1978 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1978 June 29 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1978 November 20 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1979 March 22 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1979 June 14 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1979 November 29 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1980 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1980 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1980 December 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1981 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1981 June 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1981 October 31 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1981 November 30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1982 March 29 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1982 June 7 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1982 June 28 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1982 November 29 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1983 April 7 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1983 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1983 October 28 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1983 November 28 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1984 March 26 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1984 July 9 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1984 November 26 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1985 February 5; April 3; June 17 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1985 October 28; November 25 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1986 March 31 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1986 June 16 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1986 November 24 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1987 February 17 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1987 Mach 30 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1987 June 15 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1987 October 7 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1987 October 27 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1987 November 24 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1987 December 15 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1988 March 16 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1988 March 17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Executive committee, 1988 May 9 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1988 June 24 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1988 June 29 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1988 September 15 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Executive committee, 1988 September 29 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1988 November 30 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1989 January 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1989 March 16 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1989 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1989 June 15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1989 June 28 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1989 September 14 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1989 November 29 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1989 December 18 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Executive committee, 1990 February 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1990 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1990 March 21 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1990 June 14 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1990 June 27 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1990 September 6 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Finance committee, 1990 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1990 November 28 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1992 June 24 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1992 November 23 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1993 March 5 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda - Executive committee, 1993 June 29 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1993 November 18 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1994 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1994 November 29 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1995 March 6 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1996 July 18 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1996 July 18 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1996 November 19 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1998 March 11 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1998 June 10 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1998 December 14 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1999 March 10 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1999 June 15-16 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1999 November 10 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2000 March 7 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2000 June 7 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2000 November 13 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2001 February 12 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2001 June 4 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2001 November 19 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2002 March 4 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2002 June 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2002 December 4 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2003 March 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2003 June 9 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2003 November 10 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2004 March 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2004 June 17 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2004 November 16 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2005 March 8 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2005 June 7 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2005 November 15 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2006 March 28 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2006 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2006 November 29 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2007 April 4 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2007 November 29 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2008 March 6 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 2008 June 3 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1946-1989; 3
    - Minutes, 1946-1952 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1953-1963 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1964-1971 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1971-1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files (Blue Books), 1989-1998; 4
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1989 July -1990 February (Box 18, Folder 1-24)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1990 March-October (Box 19, Folder 1-26)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1990 November-1991 May (Box 20, Folder 1-17)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1991 June-October (Box 21, Folder 1-14)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1991 November-1992 April (Box 22, Folder 1-17)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1992 May-September (Box 23, Folder 1-16)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1992 September-1993 February (Box 24, Folder 1-14)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1993 February-May (Box 25, Folder 1-14)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1993 May-September (Box 26, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1993 September-December (Box 27, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1994 January-March (Box 28, Folder 1-9)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1994 March-June (Box 29, Folder 1-11)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1994 June-November (Box 30, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1994 November-1995 March (Box 31, Folder 1-13)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1995 April-August (Box 32, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1995 August-November (Box 33, Folder 1-10)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1995 November-1996 February (Box 34, Folder 1-11)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1996 February-May (Box 35, Folder 1-7)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1996 June-September (Box 36, Folder 1-8)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1996 October-1997 January (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1997 February-May (Box 38, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1997 June-October (Box 39, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological correspondence (Blue Books), 1997 October-1998 February (Box 40, Folder 1-12)
  - Former Board of Directors Members, 1965-1997; 5
    - Michael L. Ainslie, 1986-1994 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Michael L. Ainslie, 1994-1997 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - David O. Bein, 1984-1990 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - David O. Bein, 1990-1993 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - David O. Bein, 1993-1996 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Michael Collins, 1989-1993 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Stuart W. Cragin, 1965-1969 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Stuart W. Cragin, 1970-1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Lawrence Cremin, 1986-1990 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Jarvis Cromwell, 1965-1972 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Jarvis Cromwell, 1973-1982 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Jarvis Cromwell, 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Daniel P. Davison, 1974-1980 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Daniel P. Davison, 1981-1987 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Barbara Hauptfuhrer, 1976-1980 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Barbara Hauptfuhrer, 1981-1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - John Heiman, 1988-1993 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - John Heiman, 1994-1996 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Warren F. Hellman, 1971-1979 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Warren F. Hellman, 1980-1990 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Alice S. Ilchman, 1984-1988 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Alice S. Ilchman, 1989-1995 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Maximilian Kempner, 1971-1980 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Maximilian Kempner, 1981-1991 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Gertrude G. Michelson, 1973-1980 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Gertrude G. Michelson, 1981-1987 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Gertrude G. Michelson, 1988-1993 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Gertrude G. Michelson, 1994-1995 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Gertrude G. Michelson, 1996-1997 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - James C. Pitney, 1965-1975 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - William M. Rees, 1965-1973 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - William M. Rees, 1974-1980 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - William M. Rees, 1981-1996 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Donald M. Stewart, 1987-1992 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Richard E. Stewart, 1972-1980 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Richard E. Stewart, 1981-1990 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Building and Office Files, 1986-2000; 6
    - 50 Rockefeller Plaza - Termination of Lease, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza, 1986-1987 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Bills, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Bills, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Bills, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Budgets, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Build-out, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Floor plan, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Office Plans - 2017:FA785:003 - Architectural Drawings, 1986 (Folder 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted - pending stabillization of drawings.
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Herbert Construction contract, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Invitation to bidders, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Jan Hird Pokorny Architects and Planners - Contract, 1986-1987 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Jan Hird Pokorny Architects and Planners - Photographs of Markle Foundation office, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Real estate brokers, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Time Warner correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Time Warner, 1986-1992 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Time Warner, 1993-1998 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Time Warner, 1993-1998 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Lease - Termination of lease, 1999-2000 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Library renovation, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Minutes of jobsite meetings, 1986-1987 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Move, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Refurbishment, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Renovation of west office storage and file room, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - 75 Rockefeller Plaza - Time Warner building correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Norman Diekman - Furniture, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Fire safety and insurance requirements, 1993-1997 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Restricted material.
    - Geller Lease - Washington DC, 1993-1995 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Phone system, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Security system, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Telecommunications cooperative network, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Micsellaneous Files, 7
    - Markle Foundation - Incorporation, 1927-1978 (Box 50A, Folder 1)
    - Markle Foundation - Incorporation - Certified copy, 1927 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Markle Foundation - Charter of Incorporation, 1927-1988 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Markle Foundation - Charter, Constitution, By-Laws, 1946-1978 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Markle Foundation - Certificate or Type - New York State, 1970-1973 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Markle Foundation tax status, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Markle family relatives and beneficiaries, correspondence, 1975-1993 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Trust Funds - Bankers Trust Company, Foundation as residuary legatee, 1949-1973 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Lilian Barber Trust - Bankers Trust Company, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Lavina E. Emerick Trust - Bankers Trust Company, 1951-1977 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Hulda N. Laines Trust - Bankers Trust Company, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - John Markle Estate Trusts, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Frank Pecci Trust - Bankers Trust Company, 1949-1980 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Eleanor J. Pollock - Bankers Trust Company, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Public Relations - Owen Comora, 1992-1994 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Confidentiality / Non-Disclosure Agreement, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 50th Anniversary of Markle Scholars, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Peter L. Bernstein, Financial Consultant correspondence, 1980-1998 (Box 51, Folder 6-9)
    - Peter L. Bernstein, Financial Consultant correspondence, 1980-1998 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - Roger G. Kennedy correspondence, 1980-1992 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report correspondence - Julia Vitullo-Martin, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
- Grant and Grantee Files, 1971-1999; 2; 52.48 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Contains grant administration files, general files, and grant-related files and correspondence.
  - American Film Institute, 1972-1996 (Box 53, Folder 1-3)
  - American Political Channel (APC), 1994-1995 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Andrus Gernotology Center, University of Southern California, 1985-1988 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Annenberg Washington Program in Communications Policy Studies, 1982-1995 (Box 53, Folder 6-7)
  - Annenberg Washington Program in Communications Policy Studies - Paula Newberg project, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Annenberg Washington Program in Communications Policy Studies - Technologies of Electronic Media, 1987 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Apple Computer, 1987-1990 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Apple Computer - Multimedia Lab, 1991-1993 (Box 54, Folder 4-8)
  - Apple Publishers Forum, 1992 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Archstone Partners, L.P., 1991-1995 (Box 55, Folder 2-3)
  - Arizona State University, 1988-1993 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Arlen Communications, Gary Arlen, 1987-1995 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Asia Foundation, 1977-1993 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Aspen Film Festival, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G88335 - Conferences on Telecommunications Policy, 1988-1992 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    Support for conferences on telecommunications policy.
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G88335 - Seniornet conference, 1991 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G92112 - Computer policy Summit, 1992-1994 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    "To conduct two conferences on issues of importance in developing areas of communications".
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G92112 - Electronic Citizenship, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G93115 - Seminars, 1992-1998 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    "Support for a series of four seminars to advance communications in the public interest, at least one of which will support the Carter Commission on Radio and Television Policy".
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G93115 - "Designing an Information Bill of Rights and Responsibilities", 1993 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G93115 - Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Aspen Institute - Grant G94309 - Planning meeting for "Impact of Interactive Communications", 1993-1994 (Box 56, Folder 6)